Batt, Rosemary, Call Center Research Materials /4318
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Rosemary Batt Call Center Research Materials
2000-2008
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Batt, Rosemary
/4318
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Research (document genres), research notes.
8596639
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 08, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Rosemary Batt is the Alice Hanson Cook Professor of Women and Work at the ILR School, Cornell University. She is a Professor in Human Resource Studies and International and Comparative Labor. She received her BA from Cornell University and her Ph.D. from the Sloan School of Management, Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Her research focuses on comparative international studies of management and employment relations, with particular attention to the impact of financialization on management and employment and the globalization and restructuring of service industries and its impact on low wage workers. She previously coordinated the Global Call Center Project/. She has written extensively on human resource practices and their effect on firm performance, the quality of jobs, and wage and employment outcomes.
Her work has appeared in such journals as the Academy of Management Journal, British Journal of Industrial Relations, the European Journal of Industrial Relations, Industrial and Labor Relations Review, Industrial Relations, International Journal of Human Resource Management, and Personnel Psychology. She is co-author of Private Equity at Work (2014) with Eileen Appelbaum; co-editor of the Oxford Handbook on Work and Organization and co-author of The New American Workplace: Transforming Work Systems in the United States, Cornell University Press.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4283/001: ILR School Extension Division (Buffalo, N.Y.) Lou Jean Fleron Files /4322: Rosemary Batt Gender and Global Change Program Files /4322 AV: Rosemary Batt Gender and Global Change Program Audio-Visual Materials
Batt, Rosemary L.
8596639
- CWA: 1995 Bargaining (Box 1, Folder 1)
- CWA: 1998 Bargaining on Service Representative Issues, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- CWA: AT&T, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- CWA Agreements, 1998-2005 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- CWA: Amazon, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- CWA: Airline Reservation Call Centers, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- CWA: The Alliance, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- CWA: Building A Practical Movement, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- CWA: Bungling on Building At AT&T (Box 1, Folder 9)
- CWA: Call Center Workers, 1993-1998 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- CWA: Changing Information Services, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- CWA: Conference on Collective Bargaining, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- CWA Conference on Customer Service, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- CWA Conference on the Information Super Highway, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- CWA Conference on Marketing 1997,2001 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- CWA: Contracts and Wages 1984-1997 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- CWA: Customs Service Professionals, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- CWA: Defending Workers Rights In the Global Economy, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- CWA: District 1, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- CWA Executive Board Repeat on Union Management Participation, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- CWA: Global Action Week, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- CWA: Goldman, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- CWA: Graphic Artists Guild, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- CWA History: A Brief Review, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- CWA: Locally Speaking, 2001-2005 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- CWA News, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- CWA News, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- CWA News, 2003-2005 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- CWA: Our Future at AT&T: CWA Action Plan, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- CWA Pamphlets, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- CWA: Press Releases, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- CWA At Southwestern Bell, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- CWA: Sprint, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- CWA Tear Down The Wall at Verizon, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- CWA: Telecommunications Industry, 1994-2000 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- CWA: Telecommuting, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- CWA: The Union Difference, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- CWA: Update, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- CWA: Verizon, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- CWA: Verizon Job Security Arbitration, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- CWA: Website Print-Outs, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- CWA: Workplace of the Future Forms, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Articles on Outsourcing (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Asian Emergence; The World's Back Office?, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Australia, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Berlin, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Business Week Articles February 3, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Business Week Articles on Outsourcing, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- CCA Research Institute, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- CIO.com Articles, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- CWU, 2001-2005 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Calcom, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Call-Routing Schemes for Call-Center Outsourcing, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Convereys, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- The Deregulation of International Trucking in the European Union, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- The Effect of HRM Practices and R&D Investment in Workers Productivity, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Employment, working Conditions and Company Organization, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- European Call Centre Standards For Training And Qualification, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Global Call Centers, 2003-2005 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- The Globalization of Software Services, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Human Resource Architecture, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- India, 2002-2005 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Indian Clips, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Jobs on the Move, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Lessons from the Failure of U.S. Electricity Restructuring (Box 2, Folder 20)
- New Product Development in a Global Knowledge Network, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- New Technology and Changing Organizational Forms, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- No Passage to India? (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Offsharing in the Semiconductor Industry, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Printing at an Industry, Commodity, and Activity, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Product Market Competition and Human Resource Practices (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Refashioning Organizational Boundaries, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- The Rise of the 'Network Organization' and the Decline of Discretion, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Some Sectoral and Locational Factors in the Development of Call Centres in the U.S.A. and The Netherlands, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Survey of the Telecommunications Industry, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Tosca Project, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Telecommunications Industry, 1992-2005 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- UK, 2001-2004 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- UK Call and Contact Centre Industry, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- UK: Call Centre Practice not Theory, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- UK: Health and Safety in Call Centres, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- UK: Trade Unions and Call Centres, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- The U.S. Call Centre Industry, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- U.S. - India Outsource Dismissals, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Uni: Union Network International, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- UNI Pamphlets, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Unifi, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Unison (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Various Articles February 1, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Various Articles May 2, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Work Opportunities for Women in for Information Society, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 46)